# RUEI-PU(ALLEN) KOU

905-966-3228 www.AllenKou.info imakou@gmail.com

#### **PROFILE**

5+ years of experience in front-end development (RWD, SPA). I have 3 years of working experience in developing medium web applications such as CMS and CRM apps by React.js and other tools such as Git and Docker to enhance my developing performance. Currently, React.js and Redux are the major front-end tech stack that I am focusing on. Occasionally, I build mobile apps as my side-projects by Flutter. Please visit my online resume for more showcases at <a href="https://www.AllenKou.info">https://www.AllenKou.info</a>

#### **SKILLS**

Javascript (ES 6/7). ReactJS. Redux. Node.JS. Express. GraphQL (with Apollo and Prisma). React Native. Flutter. Git. Docker. Jest. Enzyme. React Testing Library (RTL). Ant Design. Material UI. Bootstrap. HTML. CSS (SASS). Puppeteer. RWD. AWS. Circle CI.

#### **EDUCATION**

Diploma in Computer Programmer Seneca College Toronto, ON,Canada | 2015.01 – 2015.07 Bachelor in Information management Hsing-Wu University Taipei, Taiwan | 2007.08 – 2011.08

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# REACT DEVELOPER - NEXJ SYSTEM INC | NORTH YORK, ON, CANADA | 2019.03 - PRESENT

- Built UI components by React.js primely.
- Built well organized components by advance technics such as Context, Hooks, HOC, and RenderProps.
- Pursued concise-code style by pure components and hooks.
- Implemented component tests by Jest, Enzyme and React Testing Library (RTL).
- Cooperated with PMs and designers to improve UI / UX

#### WEB DEVELOPER - GELENK NETWORK INC | MARKHAM, ON, CANADA | 2017.09 - 2018.12

- Developed web message APP with feature including Realtime SMS or MMS sending and receiving, user-friendly UI implemented by Material UI, drafts auto-save, and built-in message templates using React and Redux.
- Develop a telephone configuration CMS named GenVoice Portal wth features including pie charts and graph usage visualization by BizChart, bills expiration as formatted PDF files, and a IVR (Interactive Voice Response) system with a visual keypad using React and Redux.
- Provided React and Redux training to new staff.
- Work collaboratively with a team of back end developer, system architect and project manager.

# FRONT END DEVELOPER – UNIVERSITY OF WATERLOO – CONRAD BUSINESS CENTRE WATERLOO, ON, CANADA | 2017.05 – 2017.08

- Implemented features based on React and Redux
- Practiced features including dynamic data graph, real-time chatting (Twilio's API)
- Built BDD testing practices (e2e by Cucumber, Selenium and Mocha)
- Cooperated with UI/UX team and enhanced website's components to be more user friendly

## WEB DEVELOPER - DIGIM | TAIPEI, TAIWAN | 2014.01 - 2014.05

- Developed retina display friendly RWD pages
- Collaborated with the creative and back-end teams
- Provide Sass and HTML template(ERB) training to colleagues

## WEB DEVELOPER - REXHOLIDAY | TAIPEI, TAIWAN | 2013.07 - 2013.12

- Collaborated with stakeholders to improve an internal itinerary system
- Developed internal IT devices plan
- Enhanced colleagues' workflow using SaaS

# WEB DEVELOPER - WEBIKE.TW | TAIPEI, TAIWAN | 2013.01 - 2013.06

- Designed and developed the first version prototype of eCommerce website base on Magneto
- Organized over 300k primitive data to MySQL database
- Deployed project to EC2 instances in LAMP environment on AWS
- Made back-up plans and optimized servers' performances